(upbeat music)
- Hello English learners,
welcome back to another podcast
with us here at English
Pod, my name is Marco.
- And I'm Erica.
- And today we're gonna be
looking at a very popular topic,
something that everyone has
to do at least once in their life.
- That's right, we're talking about mobile
phones and getting a mobile phone plan.
- Right, so you have a mobile phone,
you need to get a plan or you need to do
something in order to make it work, right?
- Yes, and in this lesson, we're going to
learn some language to help you do that.
- All right, so let's start with the
language on vocabulary preview.
- vocabulary preview.
In the dialogue, we're
going to compare two types
of mobile phone plans, the pre-paid
plan and the monthly rate plan.
- Okay, so we have two
types of plans, pre-paid.
- Pre-paid plan.
- Okay, a pre-paid plan.
- Well, a pre-paid plan,
basically, just like the
name suggests, you pay
before you use the minutes.
- So you maybe you have to buy a card
and then you can use maybe 20
minutes or 30 minutes or 100 minutes.
- Exactly.
- And then when you run out of money
or you use all your minutes, you
can buy another card and like that.
- Yeah, but the monthly
rate plan is different.
- So the monthly rate plan
you have to pay each month.
- Right, at the end of each month.
- At the end of each
month, and what do you pay?
- You pay for everything you used.
- You get a bill at the end of the month.
- Exactly.
- Okay, so very interesting.
These are the ways that
mobile phone plans usually work.
And well, now it's time for us to
listen to this dialogue for the first time.
We are going to be listening
as a shopper is looking
to buy maybe a mobile phone
or get a mobile phone plan.
(upbeat music)
- Yeah, I just moved here and
I'd like to activate my cell phone
and I'm not sure if I should go with
a prepaid plan or a monthly rate plan.
- I see.
Well, can I have a look at your phone?
Unfortunately, this phone
can't be using the US.
It's not compatible with our 3G network.
- What?
- Really?
- I don't really want to
have to buy a new phone.
- Well, you're in luck.
You see, if you sign up for our three year
plan, we'll throw in a handset for free.
- Really?
- What's the cash?
- There's no cash.
You just choose a plan, sign a
three year contract, and that's it.
Actually, we're running
a special promotion right
now and we're giving
away a BlackBerry curve
with our special mega
value for the dollar plan.
- So what does this plan include?
- Well, you get 900 any time minutes
and you can also enjoy free mobile to
mobile calling to other tell mobile clients.
A thousand text messages per month
and unlimited evening and weekend minutes.
Oh, and we also offer a rollover option.
- Wow, all this for $40 per month.
- That's right, plus the activation
fee and the emergency services fee.
The monthly service fee.
Oh, and any charges for extra minutes.
And...
(upbeat music)
- Well, it sounds like a lot
more than $40, doesn't it?
- This is very common.
They always say that it's a very low price
and they always have
these hidden charges, right?
- Yep, you're right.
So why don't we look
at some of the language
they were using in the dialogue
now in language takeaway?
- Language takeaway.
- All right, a language takeaway today.
We're gonna be looking
at four very basic words
that are used in this whole mobile phone
context and the first one is activate.
To activate my cell phone.
- All right, so you have
to activate your cell phone.
- That's right, you have to
make the cell phone work.
- So basically you make it work.
Now, can you only apply
this to mobile phones?
- No, there's many things that
you must activate to make work.
For example, you must activate
to your computer software.
- Okay, or maybe you have
to activate your credit card.
- Or activate your bank account.
- So usually you do this for the
first time before you start using it.
- Yeah, like imagine your
mobile phone is sleeping, right?
And you need to activate
it to make it start working.
- But you only do it once.
- Right, only once.
- Okay, we talk about
mobile phone or we say the
cell phone, but this also
has a specific name, right?
- That's right, a handset.
- Hand set.
- A handset.
- So the device, the phone,
you can call it a handset.
- Exactly.
- All right, a very easy word, but
it's kind of a little bit more technical.
- Yeah.
Now, one of the things
they were talking about
with this monthly rate
plan was a rollover option.
- Rollover.
- A rollover option.
- So what is this rollover option about?
- Well, okay, I'll give you an example.
Let's say you have 500 minutes each month,
and you only use four
of them in this month.
100 of those minutes
can rollover, can move
over to the next month,
then I have 600 minutes.
- So basically the minutes that you don't
use, you can still use the following month.
- Right.
- Okay, so that's a rollover plan.
Now we might recognize
the verb to rollover, right?
So it's very similar to physically
move from one place to another.
- Yep.
- All right, rollover.
And now in the end, we
talked about many types of fees.
- That's right, activation fee.
- Okay, or we also had
emergency services fee.
- Mm-hmm.
- So what is a fee?
- A fee is the amount of money
you must pay for a service.
- Okay, so this is
important, it's for a service.
- Yep.
- You can't pay a fee for
something you can touch.
- Okay, so if I go
to the store, I don't
say, what is the fee
of this bottle of water?
- Right, what's the fee for
filling this bottle of water?
- Okay, so for a service.
- Yes, for an action.
- All right, very good.
So I think it's time for us
to listen to this dialogue.
Again, we're gonna slow it
down because it was a little bit fast
and then we'll come back
and look at some great phrases.
(upbeat music)
- Hi there, can I help you?
- Yeah, I've just moved here and
I'd like to activate my cell phone.
And I'm not sure if I should go with
a prepaid plan or a monthly rate plan.
- I see.
Well, can I have a look at your phone?
Unfortunately, this phone
can't be used in the U.S.
It's not compatible with our 3G network.
- What?
- Really?
- I don't really want to
have to buy a new phone.
- Well, you're in luck, you see?
If you sign up for our three-year
plan, we'll throw in a handset for free.
- Really?
What's the catch?
- There's no catch.
You just choose a plan?
Sign a three-year contract and that's it.
Actually, we're running a
special promotion right now
and we're giving away a blackberry
curve with our special mega value $40 plan.
- So what does this plan include?
- Well, you get 900 any time minutes
and you can also enjoy
free mobile-to-mobile calling
to other cell-mobile
clients, 1,000 text messages
per month and unlimited
evening and weekend minutes.
Oh, and we also offer a rollover option.
- Wow, all this for $40 per month.
- That's right.
Plus the activation fee, the emergency
services fee, the monthly service fee.
Oh, and any charges for extra minutes.
And.
(upbeat music)
- Well, you know, there
are some interesting phrases
in this dialogue and a
lot of them can be used
when you're talking about an
negotiation or a contract or a deal.
- All right, great.
So let's take a look at these
phrases in Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
Okay, the first phrase that we
have on Fluency Builder today
was the problem that she
had with her mobile phone
was that it wasn't
compatible with a 3G network.
- Okay, to be compatible with.
- To be compatible with.
- Now this word compatible
means that it works well
with something else.
- Exactly, now there's a lot of things that
you can use this phrase compatible with.
Together with, you know, people, things.
So I wanna be here a few examples now.
Example one.
Our application is compatible
with most smartphones.
Example two.
- My roommate and I
are just not compatible.
All she ever does is study.
And I like to say a blatant party.
- Example three.
- I'm sorry, your computer is not
compatible with our software, it's too old.
- Okay, great example.
So compatible with very clear end.
It's very useful.
- That's right.
- Now, what about the next phrase?
- Well, you know, the girl
was hearing about all of
these great things that
are included in the contract.
And she asked, what's the catch?
- What's the catch?
So she was asking for the catch.
What is the catch?
- Well, good thing you asked.
A catch is something
negative, something that's
hidden that makes the
deal seem not so great.
- Okay, so if somebody offers me a new car,
they say you can have this new for free.
- Okay, well, that seems
too good to be true.
So what is the catch?
- The catch is that I
can only drive it at night.
- Okay, that's kind of annoying.
- Right, yeah.
- So that's the catch.
There's like a condition.
- Yep.
- Now she asked about the catch and well,
she said, well, there's no catch, you know?
It's, you just signed the contract.
And then the salesman told
the lady that she is in luck.
You're in luck to be in luck.
- Well, okay, I think we can really
understand the meaning, right?
When you're in luck,
something lucky has happened.
- Right, you're having good fortune.
But how do we use it?
- So maybe you're looking for a very
special bottle of wine for dinner tonight.
- Yep, it's very rare.
- Okay, and you go into this little store
and all of a sudden you're
in luck, you found it there.
- Exactly.
- Okay.
- This phrase is actually most commonly
used in the second person, you're in luck.
You are in luck, you are in luck tonight.
- Yeah, and it usually
when someone asks you
for something then
you say you're in luck.
- You're in luck, I have it.
Or you're in luck, I
have the very last one.
- Exactly.
- All right, and now to end a fluency
builder, we have one more phrase.
And so it was when the salesman
said, we'll throw in a handset for free.
- All right, to throw something in.
- So if she signs the contract,
he will throw in a free handset.
It means to include something for free.
- Okay, so you can say,
if you buy this house,
I'll throw in the dog,
the dog for free, right?
So to throw in, to include for free.
- Right.
- Okay, all right, so great phrases
and I think we understand them now.
So let's listen to this
dialogue for the very last time.
(upbeat music)
- Yeah, I just moved here and
I'd like to activate my cell phone
and I'm not sure if I should go with
a prepaid plan or a monthly rate plan.
- I see.
Well, can I have a look at your phone?
Unfortunately, this phone
can't be used in the US.
It's not compatible with our 3G network.
- What?
- Really?
- I don't really want to
have to buy a new phone.
- Well, you're in luck.
You see, if you sign up for our 3-year
plan, we'll throw in a handset for free.
- Really?
- What's the cash?
- There's no cash.
You just choose a plan, sign
a 3-year contract, and that's it.
Actually, we're running a
special promotion right now
and we're giving away a blackberry
curve with our special mega-value $40 plan.
- So what does this plan include?
- Well, you get 900 anytime minutes
and you can also enjoy free mobile-to-mobile
calling to other-to-mobile clients.
A thousand text messages per month
and unlimited evening and weekend minutes.
Oh, and we also offer a rollover option.
- Wow, all this for $40 per month.
- That's right, plus the activation fee
in the emergency services
fee, the monthly service fee.
Oh, and any charges
for extra minutes and...
- Mobile phones.
This is very common in
the United States, right?
These monthly plans.
- Yeah, most places where I have lived,
it's much more common
to pay as you go, right?
To have a prepaid plan.
But in the States, almost everyone
goes with the monthly plan.
Maybe it's because in order to have a
monthly plan, you need to have a credit card.
- You might be on to something, right?
So if you don't have a credit card or maybe
you're 18, you can't get a monthly plan.
So you gotta do this prepaid plan.
- Yeah, you know, another interesting thing
that I've noticed
when living in different
countries and seeing mobile
phone habits, Americans
and North Americans
respond very differently
to a ringing mobile phone
than other people do.
- How so?
- For example, if I was in a meeting in
America and my phone rang and I answered it,
people might think that I was very
rude to answer the phone in a meeting.
But, you know, here, when we're
living in China, it's totally normal.
It's, you know, everyone does it.
That's the polite thing
to do, answer your phone.
- Right, and I think
that's absolutely true.
And maybe it's because in North America,
you have this voicemail
option for your mobile phone.
- Yeah, and everyone has it.
- Everyone has it.
So if it's something very
important, then the person
will leave you a voicemail
message and then you
will know what it's about
or you can call them back.
But here, I guess, or in other countries,
maybe they don't have that option.
So they need to answer every call.
- Yeah, it's interesting.
An interesting sort of cultural
difference in the way we use our phones.
But what about listeners in your country?
Do you answer the phone
immediately or do you let it ring?
- Right, or maybe do you see who's
calling and maybe just not answer it?
- Yeah, I screen your calls.
- Just screen a call.
- So come to our
website, englishpod.
com, let us know what
your mobile phone habits are.
And also, if you have
any questions or doubts.
- Yeah, Marco and I are always
there to answer your questions.
So until next time, thanks
for listening, and goodbye.
- Bye.
(upbeat music)